<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Achim Ahrens</title>
    <link>https://achimahrens.de/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Achim Ahrens</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://achimahrens.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://achimahrens.de/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://achimahrens.de/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>https://achimahrens.de/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://achimahrens.de/elements/</guid>
      <description>test Font Sizes A A A A A A A A 6rem
(96px) 5rem
(80px) 3rem
(48px) 2.25rem
(36px) 1.5rem
(24px) 1.25rem
(20px) 1rem
(16px) .875rem
(14px) Type Samples Head&amp;shy;line Sub&amp;shy;head&amp;shy;line Level 1 Heading One page to rule them all...well, not really. This page displays sample typography and page elements to illustrate their style. Things like headings and paragraphs showing the beautiful type scale, form elements, tabular data, and image layouts just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://achimahrens.de/header/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://achimahrens.de/header/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Hugo theme you&amp;rsquo;ll want to hang out with. 🇫🇷
The page you are reading is based on a markdown file- look in content/about/ to edit. There, look inside the header, main, and sidebar folders to get started building your own &amp;ldquo;about&amp;rdquo; page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://achimahrens.de/sidebar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://achimahrens.de/sidebar/</guid>
      <description>** index doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just front matter above. See about/list.html in the layouts folder **</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://achimahrens.de/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://achimahrens.de/about/</guid>
      <description>About me I am a Senior Data Scientist and Post-Doctoral Researcher at the Public Policy Group, ETH Zurich, and Immigration Policy Lab (ETH/Stanford). Previously, I was a Post-Doc at the Economic and Social Research Institute, Dublin. I hold an MSc in Economics from University of Edinburgh and a PhD in Economics from Heriot-Watt University.
Research I have worked on empirical projects in a wide range of fields including housing markets, urban economics and energy economics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://achimahrens.de/policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://achimahrens.de/policy/</guid>
      <description>Policy Reports Evaluating the Effects of Cash-Based Interventions on the Integration of Vulnerable Venezuelan Migrants in Peru: Key Findings Using a Multidimensional Approach to Measure Migrant Integration Outcomes.
With Monica Aguilar Folch, Ace Dela Cruz, Jobst Koehler, Morgane Reina and Karla Sulca (IOM) and Dominik Hangartner, Marine Casalis, Rodrigo Sanchez (ETH Zurich).
Abtract This study report analyzes the effect of the multi-purpose cash-based intervention (CBI) program implemented by the International Organization for Migration (IOM) in Peru on migrants’ psychological, economic, political, social, linguistic, and navigational integration, as well as in other outcome variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://achimahrens.de/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://achimahrens.de/research/</guid>
      <description>Selected Publications Ahrens, A., Hansen, C.B., Schaffer, M.E., Wiemann, T., Forthcoming. ddml: Double/debiased machine learning in Stata. Stata Journal. ↪arxiv version
Ahrens, A., Hansen, C.B., Schaffer, M.E., 2023. pystacked: Stacking generalization and machine learning in Stata. Stata Journal, 23(4), pp.909-931. ↪Link
Ahrens, A. and Lyons, S., 2021. Do rising rents lead to longer commutes? A gravity model of commuting flows in Ireland. Urban Studies, 58(2), pp.264-279. ↪Link
O’Toole, C., Martinez-Cillero, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://achimahrens.de/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://achimahrens.de/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://achimahrens.de/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://achimahrens.de/software/</guid>
      <description>Stata Programs The package lassopack implements lasso ( Tibshirani 1996), square-root lasso ( Belloni et al. 2011), elastic net ( Zou &amp;amp; Hastie 2005), ridge regression ( Hoerl &amp;amp; Kennard 1970), adaptive lasso ( Zou 2006) and post-estimation OLS. lassopack also supports logistic lasso.
pdslasso offers methods to facilitate causal inference in structural models. The package allows to select control variables and/or instruments from a large set of variables in a setting where the researcher is interested in estimating the causal impact of one or more (possibly endogenous) causal variables of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://achimahrens.de/talking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://achimahrens.de/talking/</guid>
      <description>Recent talks 08/23 EEA-ESEM (Barcelona, Spain) 06/23 International Association for Applied Econometrics (Oslo, Norway) 06/23 Machine Learning in Program Evaluation, High-dimensionality and Visualization Techniques (LISER, Luxembourg) 05/23 Society of Labor Economists (Philadelhia, US) 03/23 University of Bern seminar (Sociology) 11/22 Stata Conference (Bern, CH) 10/22 AI+Economics Workshop (ETH Zürich) 9/22 European Association of Labour Economists (Padova, Italy) 8/22 European Economic Association (Milan, Italy) 6/22 Barcelona School of Economics (Spain) 6/22 Workshop Job Search and the Labor Market (CH) 5/22 University of Bath seminar 3/22 Applied ML Days (ETH Zürich) Workshops I give workshops on causal inference &amp;amp; machine learning in R and Stata:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why apéro?</title>
      <link>https://achimahrens.de/main/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://achimahrens.de/main/</guid>
      <description>** index doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just front matter above. See about/list.html in the layouts folder **</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work in progress</title>
      <link>https://achimahrens.de/ongoing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://achimahrens.de/ongoing/</guid>
      <description>Working papers Model averaging and double machine learning
With Christian B Hansen, Mark E Schaffer, Thomas Wiemann
Abstract: &amp;nbsp This paper discusses pairing double/debiased machine learning (DDML) with stacking, a model averaging method for combining multiple candidate learners, to estimate structural parameters. We introduce two new stacking approaches for DDML: short-stacking exploits the cross-fitting step of DDML to substantially reduce the computational burden and pooled stacking enforces common stacking weights over cross-fitting folds.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
